<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
  <row name="Decipher Writing">
    <trait>CONCENTRATE</trait>
    <trait>EXPLORATION</trait>
    <trait>SECRET</trait>
    <comment>You attempt to decipher complicated writing or literature on an obscure topic.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="EARN INCOME">
    <trait>DOWNTIME</trait>
    <comment>You use one of your skills to make money during downtime.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="IDENTIFY MAGIC">
    <trait>CONCENTRATE</trait>
    <trait>EXPLORATION</trait>
    <trait>SECRET</trait>
    <comment>Once you discover that an item, location, or ongoing effect is magical, you can spend 10 minutes to try to identify the particulars of its magic.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="LEARN A SPELL">
    <trait>CONCENTRATE</trait>
    <trait>EXPLORATION</trait>
    <comment>You can gain access to a new spell of your tradition from someone who knows that spell or from magical writing like a spellbook or scroll.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="RECALL KNOWLEDGE">
    <trait>CONCENTRATE</trait>
    <trait>SECRET</trait>
    <comment>The following skills can be used to Recall Knowledge, getting information about the listed topics.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="SUBSIST">
    <trait>DOWNTIME</trait>
    <comment>You try to provide food and shelter for yourself, and possibly others as well, with a standard of living.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="BALANCE">
    <trait>MOVE</trait>
    <comment>You move across a narrow surface or uneven ground.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="TUMBLE THROUGH">
    <trait>MOVE</trait>
    <comment>You Stride up to your Speed. During this movement, you can try to move through the space of one enemy.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="MANEUVER IN FLIGHT">
    <trait>MOVE</trait>
    <comment>You try a difficult maneuver while flying.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="SQUEEZE">
    <trait>EXPLORATION</trait>
    <trait>MOVE</trait>
    <comment>You contort yourself to squeeze through a space so small you can barely fit through.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="BORROW AN ARCANE SPELL">
    <trait>CONCENTRATE</trait>
    <trait>EXPLORATION</trait>
    <comment>If you’re an arcane spellcaster who prepares from a spellbook, you can attempt to prepare a spell from someone else’s spellbook.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="CLIMB">
    <trait>MOVE</trait>
    <comment>You move up, down, or across an incline.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="FORCE OPEN">
    <trait>ATTACK</trait>
    <comment>Using your body, a lever, or some other tool, you attempt to forcefully open a door, window, container or heavy gate. With a high enough result, you can even smash through walls.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="GRAPPLE">
    <trait>ATTACK</trait>
    <comment>You attempt to grab a creature or object with your free hand.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="HIGH JUMP">
    <trait>MOVE</trait>
    <comment>You Stride, then make a vertical Leap.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="LONG JUMP">
    <trait>MOVE</trait>
    <comment>You Stride, then make a horizontal Leap.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="SHOVE">
    <trait>ATTACK</trait>
    <comment>You push a creature away from you.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="SWIM">
    <trait>MOVE</trait>
    <comment>You propel yourself through water.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="TRIP">
    <trait>ATTACK</trait>
    <comment>You try to knock a creature to the ground.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="DISARM">
    <trait>ATTACK</trait>
    <comment>You try to knock something out of a creature’s grasp.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="REPAIR">
    <trait>EXPLORATION</trait>
    <trait>MANIPULATE</trait>
    <comment>You spend 10 minutes attempting to fix a damaged item, placing the item on a stable surface and using the repair kit with both hands.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="CRAFT">
    <trait>DOWNTIME</trait>
    <trait>MANIPULATE</trait>
    <comment>You can make an item from raw materials.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="IDENTIFY ALCHEMY">
    <trait>CONCENTRATE</trait>
    <trait>EXPLORATION</trait>
    <trait>SECRET</trait>
    <comment>You can identify the nature of an alchemical item with 10 minutes of testing using alchemist’s tools.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="CREATE A DIVERSION">
    <trait>MENTAL</trait>
    <comment>With a gesture, a trick, or some distracting words, you can create a diversion that draws creatures’ attention elsewhere.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="IMPERSONATE">
    <trait>CONCENTRATE</trait>
    <trait>EXPLORATION</trait>
    <trait>MANIPULATE</trait>
    <trait>SECRET</trait>
    <comment>You create a disguise to pass yourself off as someone or something you are not.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="LIE">
    <trait>CONCENTRATE</trait>
    <trait>AUDITORY</trait>
    <trait>LINGUISTIC</trait>
    <trait>MENTAL</trait>
    <trait>SECRET</trait>
    <comment>You try to fool someone with an untruth.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="FEINT">
    <trait>MENTAL</trait>
    <comment>With a misleading flourish, you leave an opponent unprepared for your real attack.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="GATHER INFORMATION">
    <trait>EXPLORATION</trait>
    <trait>SECRET</trait>
    <comment>You canvass local markets, taverns, and gathering places in an attempt to learn about a specific individual or topic.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="MAKE AN IMPRESSION">
    <trait>CONCENTRATE</trait>
    <trait>EXPLORATION</trait>
    <trait>AUDITORY</trait>
    <trait>LINGUISTIC</trait>
    <trait>MENTAL</trait>
    <comment>With at least 1 minute of conversation, during which you engage in charismatic overtures, flattery, and other acts of goodwill, you seek to make a good impression on someone to make them temporarily agreeable.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="REQUEST">
    <trait>CONCENTRATE</trait>
    <trait>AUDITORY</trait>
    <trait>LINGUISTIC</trait>
    <trait>MENTAL</trait>
    <comment>You can make a request of a creature that’s friendly or helpful to you. You must couch the request in terms that the target would accept given their current attitude toward you.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="COERCE">
    <trait>CONCENTRATE</trait>
    <trait>EXPLORATION</trait>
    <trait>AUDITORY</trait>
    <trait>LINGUISTIC</trait>
    <trait>EMOTION</trait>
    <trait>MENTAL</trait>
    <comment>With threats either veiled or overt, you attempt to bully a creature into doing what you want. You must spend at least 1 minute of conversation with a creature you can see and that can either see or sense you.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="DEMORALIZE">
    <trait>CONCENTRATE</trait>
    <trait>AUDITORY</trait>
    <trait>EMOTION</trait>
    <trait>FEAR</trait>
    <trait>MENTAL</trait>
    <comment>With a sudden shout, a well-timed taunt, or a cutting putdown, you can shake an enemy’s resolve.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="ADMINISTER FIRST AID">
    <trait>MANIPULATE</trait>
    <comment>You perform first aid on an adjacent creature that is dying or bleeding.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="TREAT DISEASE">
    <trait>DOWNTIME</trait>
    <trait>MANIPULATE</trait>
    <comment>You spend at least 8 hours caring for a diseased creature.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="TREAT POISON">
    <trait>MANIPULATE</trait>
    <comment>You treat a patient to prevent the spread of poison.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="TREAT WOUNDS">
    <trait>EXPLORATION</trait>
    <trait>HEALING</trait>
    <trait>MANIPULATE</trait>
    <comment>You spend 10 minutes treating one injured living creature.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="COMMAND AN ANIMAL">
    <trait>AUDITORY</trait>
    <trait>CONCENTRATE</trait>
    <comment>You issue an order to an animal.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="PERFORM">
    <trait>CONCENTRATE</trait>
    <comment>When making a brief performance—one song, a quick dance, or a few jokes.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="CREATE FORGERY">
    <trait>DOWNTIME</trait>
    <trait>SECRET</trait>
    <comment>You create a forged document, usually over the course of a day or a week.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="CONCEAL AN OBJECT">
    <trait>MANIPULATE</trait>
    <trait>SECRET</trait>
    <comment>You hide a small object on your person (such as a weapon of light Bulk).</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="HIDE">
    <trait>SECRET</trait>
    <prereq object_class="Statement">Hide</prereq>
    <comment>You huddle behind cover or greater cover or deeper into concealment to become hidden, rather than observed.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="SNEAK">
    <trait>MOVE</trait>
    <trait>SECRET</trait>
    <comment>You can attempt to move to another place while becoming or staying undetected.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="SENSE DIRECTION">
    <trait>EXPLORATION</trait>
    <trait>SECRET</trait>
    <comment>Using the stars, the position of the sun, traits of the geography or flora, or the behavior of fauna, you can stay oriented in the wild.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="COVER TRACKS">
    <trait>CONCENTRATE</trait>
    <trait>EXPLORATION</trait>
    <trait>MOVE</trait>
    <comment>You cover your tracks, moving up to half your travel Speed.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="TRACK">
    <trait>CONCENTRATE</trait>
    <trait>EXPLORATION</trait>
    <trait>MOVE</trait>
    <comment>You follow tracks, moving at up to half your travel Speed.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="PALM AN OBJECT">
    <trait>MANIPULATE</trait>
    <comment>Palming a small, unattended object without being noticed</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="STEAL">
    <trait>MANIPULATE</trait>
    <comment>You try to take a small object from another creature without being noticed.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="DISABLE A DEVICE">
    <trait>MANIPULATE</trait>
    <comment>This action allows you to disarm a trap or another complex device.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="PICK A LOCK">
    <trait>MANIPULATE</trait>
    <comment>Opening a lock without a key</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Grab an Edge">
    <comment>reduce the damage from some falls</comment>
    <trigger>Falling</trigger>
  </row>
  <row name="Aid">
    <prereqDetails>An ally is about to use an action that requires a skill check or attack roll. The ally is willing to accept your aid, and you have prepared to help</prereqDetails>
    <comment>You try to help your ally with a task. To use this reaction, you must first prepare to help, usually by using an action during your turn. You must explain to the GM exactly how you’re trying to help, and they determine whether you can Aid your ally.</comment>
    <duration>for preparing aid: usually by using an action during your turn</duration>
    <calculations>roll = roll of trigger or decided by the GM</calculations>
    <dc>20 (by default)</dc>
    <checkCriticalSuccess>Aid modifier critical success</checkCriticalSuccess>
    <checkSuccess value="+1">Aid modifier</checkSuccess>
    <checkCriticalFailure value="-1">Aid modifier</checkCriticalFailure>
  </row>
  <row name="Crawl" subclass="SingleAction">
    <trait>Move</trait>
    <prereq>Prone</prereq>
    <prereq object_class="Statement">Minimal speed</prereq>
    <comment>You move 5 feet by crawling and continue to stay prone.</comment>
    <distance>5</distance>
  </row>
  <row name="Delay" subclass="FreeAction">
    <trigger>Start of turn</trigger>
    <comment>You wait for the right moment to act. The rest of your turn doesn’t happen yet. Instead, you’re removed from the initiative order. You can return to the initiative order as a free action triggered by the end of any other creature’s turn. This permanently changes your initiative to the new position. You can’t use reactions until you return to the initiative order.</comment>
    <changes>Initiative position</changes>
    <blocks>Acting phase of turn</blocks>
  </row>
  <row name="Drop prone" subclass="SingleAction">
    <trait>Move</trait>
    <activates>Prone</activates>
  </row>
  <row name="Escape" subclass="SingleAction">
    <trait>Attack</trait>
    <comment>You attempt to escape from being grabbed, immobilized, or restrained. Choose one creature, object, spell effect, hazard, or other impediment imposing any of those conditions on you.</comment>
    <selectsRoll argument="UnarmedAsWeapon">Melee attack roll</selectsRoll>
    <selectsRoll>Acrobatics roll</selectsRoll>
    <selectsRoll>Athletics roll</selectsRoll>
    <selectsDC>Athletics roll</selectsDC>
    <selectsDC>Thievery roll</selectsDC>
    <dc>{grabbing: athletics; tied up: thievery} dc or spell dc or dc of impediment</dc>
    <checkCriticalSuccess>Get free</checkCriticalSuccess>
    <checkCriticalSuccess value="5 feet">Stride reaction</checkCriticalSuccess>
    <checkSuccess>Get free</checkSuccess>
    <checkCriticalFailure>Blocked until next turn</checkCriticalFailure>
  </row>
  <row name="Interact" subclass="SingleAction">
    <trait>MANIPULATE</trait>
    <comment>You use your hand or hands to manipulate an object or the terrain. You can grab an unattended or stored object, open a door, or produce some similar effect. You might have to attempt a skill check to determine if your Interact action was successful.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Leap" subclass="SingleAction">
    <trait>MOVE</trait>
    <comment>You take a careful, short jump.</comment>
    <uses>Speed of character</uses>
    <calculations>horizontal distance, feet = 5 + Min(IntegerDivide(speed, 15), 2) * 5</calculations>
    <calculations>vertical distance, feet = 3</calculations>
    <calculations>horizontal distance on elevated surface, feet = 5</calculations>
  </row>
  <row name="Ready" subclass="Activity">
    <duration>2 actions</duration>
    <trait>CONCENTRATE</trait>
    <comment>You prepare to use an action that will occur outside your turn. Choose a single action or free action you can use, and designate a trigger. Your turn then ends. If the trigger you designated occurs before the start of your next turn, you can use the chosen action as a reaction (provided you still meet the requirements to use it). You can’t Ready a free action that already has a trigger.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Release" subclass="FreeAction">
    <trait>MANIPULATE</trait>
    <trait>Does not trigger reaction</trait>
    <comment>You release something you’re holding in your hand or hands. This might mean dropping an item, removing one hand from your weapon while continuing to hold it in another hand, releasing a rope suspending a chandelier, or performing a similar action.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Seek" subclass="SingleAction">
    <trait>CONCENTRATE</trait>
    <trait>SECRET</trait>
    <comment>You scan an area for signs of creatures or objects. If you’re looking for creatures, choose an area you’re scanning.</comment>
    <comment>The GM might determine you need to Seek as an activity, taking more actions or even minutes or hours if you’re searching a particularly cluttered area.</comment>
    <selects>Cone area rule 30ft</selects>
    <selects>Burst area rule 15ft</selects>
    <prereq>Line of sight</prereq>
    <usesRoll>Perception roll</usesRoll>
    <usesDC>Stealth roll</usesDC>
    <checkCriticalSuccess>Critical seek</checkCriticalSuccess>
    <checkSuccess>Success seek</checkSuccess>
  </row>
  <row name="Sense motive" subclass="SingleAction">
    <trait>CONCENTRATE</trait>
    <trait>SECRET</trait>
    <comment>You try to tell whether a creature’s behavior is abnormal. Choose one creature, and assess it for odd body language, signs of nervousness, and other indicators that it might be trying to deceive someone. You typically can’t try to Sense the Motive of the same creature again until the situation changes significantly.</comment>
    <usesRoll>Perception roll</usesRoll>
    <selectsDC>Deception roll</selectsDC>
    <dc>(deception dc of creature) or (dc of spell affecting target) or (dc from gm)</dc>
    <checkCriticalSuccess>Sense motive critical success</checkCriticalSuccess>
    <checkSuccess>Sense motive success</checkSuccess>
    <checkFailure>Sense motive failure</checkFailure>
    <checkCriticalFailure>Sense motive critical failure</checkCriticalFailure>
  </row>
  <row name="Stand" subclass="SingleAction">
    <trait>MOVE</trait>
    <comment>You stand up from prone.</comment>
    <deactivates>Prone</deactivates>
  </row>
  <row name="Step" subclass="SingleAction">
    <trait>MOVE</trait>
    <trait>Does not trigger reaction</trait>
    <prereq object_class="Statement">Minimal speed</prereq>
    <comment>You carefully move 5 feet. Unlike most types of movement, Stepping doesn’t trigger reactions, such as Attacks of Opportunity, that can be triggered by move actions or upon leaving or entering a square.</comment>
    <distance>5</distance>
  </row>
  <row name="Stride" subclass="SingleAction">
    <trait>MOVE</trait>
    <comment>You move up to your Speed.</comment>
    <uses>Speed of character</uses>
    <distance>land speed</distance>
  </row>
  <row name="Melee strike" subclass="SingleAction">
    <trait>ATTACK</trait>
    <comment>You attack with a weapon you’re wielding or with an unarmed attack, targeting one creature within your reach.</comment>
    <leadsTo>Melee attack check</leadsTo>
  </row>
  <row name="Ranged strike" subclass="SingleAction">
    <trait>ATTACK</trait>
    <comment>You attack with a weapon you’re wielding or with an unarmed attack, targeting one creature within your range.</comment>
    <leadsTo>Ranged attack check</leadsTo>
  </row>
  <row name="Take cover" subclass="SingleAction">
    <prereq object_class="Statement">Take cover</prereq>
    <comment>You press yourself against a wall or duck behind an obstacle to take better advantage of cover</comment>
    <leadsTo>Take greater cover</leadsTo>
  </row>
  <row name="Deactivate cover" subclass="FreeAction"/>
  <row name="Arrest a fall">
    <trigger>Falling</trigger>
    <prereq>Fly speed of character</prereq>
    <comment>You attempt an Acrobatics check to slow your fall.</comment>
    <leadsTo>Arrest a fall check</leadsTo>
  </row>
  <row name="Avert gaze" subclass="SingleAction">
    <comment>You avert your gaze from danger.</comment>
    <activates>Averted gaze</activates>
  </row>
  <row name="Burrow">
    <trait>MOVE</trait>
    <prereq object_class="Statement">Burrow</prereq>
    <comment>You dig your way through dirt, sand, or a similar loose material at a rate up to your burrow Speed.</comment>
    <calculations>distance = burrow speed</calculations>
  </row>
  <row name="Fly" subclass="SingleAction">
    <trait>MOVE</trait>
    <prereq>Fly speed of character</prereq>
    <comment>You move through the air up to your fly Speed. If you’re airborne at the end of your turn and did not use a Fly action this round, you fall.</comment>
    <calculations>distance = fly speed * {on the same level: 1; to hover in place: 0; to the ground: 2; upward: difficult terrain}</calculations>
  </row>
  <row name="Grab the edge">
    <trait>MANIPULATE</trait>
    <trigger object_class="Statement">Falling next to edge</trigger>
    <prereq>Unrestrained hands</prereq>
    <comment>When you fall off or past an edge or other handhold, you can try to grab it, potentially stopping your fall.</comment>
    <usesRoll>Reflex saving roll</usesRoll>
    <dc>climb dc for similar situation</dc>
    <checkCriticalSuccess>Grab the edge with critical success</checkCriticalSuccess>
    <checkSuccess>Grab the edge with success</checkSuccess>
    <checkCriticalFailure>Grab the edge with critical failure</checkCriticalFailure>
  </row>
  <row name="Mount" subclass="SingleAction">
    <trait>MOVE</trait>
    <prereq object_class="Statement">Mount</prereq>
    <comment>You move onto the creature and ride it.</comment>
    <activates>Mounted</activates>
    <activates>Lesser cover</activates>
  </row>
  <row name="Dismount" subclass="SingleAction">
    <trait>MOVE</trait>
    <prereq>Mounted</prereq>
    <comment>If you’re already mounted, you can instead use this action to dismount, moving off the mount into a space adjacent to it.</comment>
    <deactivates>Mounted</deactivates>
    <deactivates>Lesser cover</deactivates>
  </row>
  <row name="Point out" subclass="SingleAction">
    <trait>AUDITORY</trait>
    <trait>MANIPULATE</trait>
    <trait>VISUAL</trait>
    <prereq object_class="Statement">Point out</prereq>
    <comment>You indicate a creature that you can see to one or more allies, gesturing in a direction and describing the distance verbally.</comment>
    <leadsTo>Point out rule</leadsTo>
  </row>
  <row name="Raise a shield" subclass="SingleAction">
    <prereq object_class="Statement">Wielding a shield</prereq>
    <comment>You position your shield to protect yourself.</comment>
    <calculations>condition value = shield ac bonus</calculations>
    <activates>With raised shield</activates>
  </row>
  <row name="Cast spell">
    <leadsTo>Spend two air point</leadsTo>
  </row>
  <row name="Avoid notice">
    <comment>You attempt a Stealth check to avoid notice while traveling</comment>
    <trait>Exploration</trait>
    <leadsTo>Halved travel speed</leadsTo>
    <leadsTo>Stealth check</leadsTo>
  </row>
  <row name="Defend">
    <trait>Exploration</trait>
    <comment>You move at half your travel speed with your shield raised.</comment>
    <performs>Raise a shield</performs>
    <leadsTo>Halved travel speed</leadsTo>
  </row>
  <row name="Detect magic">
    <trait>CONCENTRATE</trait>
    <trait>EXPLORATION</trait>
    <prereq>Detect magic spell</prereq>
    <comment>You cast detect magic at regular intervals.</comment>
    <leadsTo>Halved travel speed</leadsTo>
    <leadsTo>Detect something with travel speed</leadsTo>
  </row>
  <row name="Follow the expert">
    <trait>AUDITORY</trait>
    <trait>CONCENTRATE</trait>
    <trait>EXPLORATION</trait>
    <trait>VISUAL</trait>
    <comment>The ally must be at least an expert in that skill and must be willing to provide assistance. While Following the Expert, you match their tactic or attempt similar skill checks. Thanks to your ally’s assistance, you can add your level as a proficiency bonus to the associated skill check, even if you’re untrained.</comment>
    <leadsTo>Follow the expert modifier</leadsTo>
  </row>
  <row name="Hustle">
    <trait>EXPLORATION</trait>
    <trait>MOVE</trait>
    <comment>You strain yourself to move at double your travel speed.</comment>
    <calculations>travel speed *= 2</calculations>
    <modifies>Travel speed</modifies>
    <uses>Constitution modifier</uses>
    <duration>Max(constitution modifier, 1) * 10 (minutes)</duration>
  </row>
  <row name="Investigate">
    <trait>CONCENTRATE</trait>
    <trait>EXPLORATION</trait>
    <comment>You seek out information about your surroundings.</comment>
    <leadsTo>Halved travel speed</leadsTo>
    <performs>Recall knowledge</performs>
  </row>
  <row name="Repeat a spell">
    <trait>CONCENTRATE</trait>
    <trait>EXPLORATION</trait>
    <comment>You repeatedly cast the same spell.</comment>
    <leadsTo>Halved travel speed</leadsTo>
  </row>
  <row name="Scout">
    <trait>CONCENTRATE</trait>
    <trait>EXPLORATION</trait>
    <comment>You scout ahead and behind the group to watch danger.</comment>
    <leadsTo>Halved travel speed</leadsTo>
    <trait>On all party</trait>
    <calculations>bonus = +1, circumstance</calculations>
    <modifies>Initiative roll</modifies>
  </row>
  <row name="Search">
    <trait>CONCENTRATE</trait>
    <trait>EXPLORATION</trait>
    <comment>You Seek meticulously for hidden doors, concealed hazards, and so on. In locations with many objects to search, you have to stop and spend significantly longer to search thoroughly</comment>
    <performs>Seek</performs>
    <leadsTo>Halved travel speed</leadsTo>
    <leadsTo>Detect something with travel speed</leadsTo>
  </row>
  <row name="Rest" subclass="Activity">
    <comment>You perform at your best when you take enough time to rest and prepare. Once every 24 hours, you can take a period of rest.</comment>
    <duration>8 hours (by default)</duration>
    <uses>Constitution modifier</uses>
    <uses>Level of character</uses>
    <calculations>hit points += Max(constitution modifier, 1) * level</calculations>
    <leadsTo>Recover hp rule</leadsTo>
    <leadsTo>Sleeping in armor</leadsTo>
    <deactivates>Fatigued</deactivates>
  </row>
  <row name="Daily preparations" subclass="Activity">
    <duration>1 hour</duration>
    <perDay>once</perDay>
    <sets>Prepared spell slots</sets>
    <calculations>focus points = maximum value</calculations>
    <calculations>uses per day for feats = maximum value</calculations>
    <changes>Focus points</changes>
    <changes>Feats of character</changes>
    <changes>equipment</changes>
    <leadsTo>Invest magic items</leadsTo>
  </row>
</root>