<?xml version="1.0"?>
<root>
  <row name="Alghollthu">
    <comment>Perhaps the oldest intelligent creatures on Golarion, the alghollthus ruled vast empires in the depths of the world’s oceans for eons before the first humans came to be. In fact, according to some of their wall carvings, they created the first human beings. Whether or not this claim is true is impossible to prove, but these creatures — from the sinister aboleths to their shape-changing rulers, the veiled masters—have certainly been a part of the world for a long, long time. Moreover, their claim to have existed on Golarion before the gods themselves turned their divine eyes upon the world carries some disturbing implications.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Demon">
    <comment>Normally bound to the Abyss, demons can be found wherever cults or evil spellcasters exist to call them to this world. Two notable locations, the Worldwound in the north and the Tanglebriar in southern Kyonin, deserve special mention, for here the demons of the Abyss have established lasting presences.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Devil">
    <comment>Although the rulers of Cheliax maintain that Hell is but a blueprint and devilkind is just a tool the clever spellcasters of House Thrune use to maintain control over their nation (as well as their decadent lifestyle), devils have an insidious hold over that nation. With the state formally devoted to Asmodeus and powerful orders of Hellknights serving as mercenary arbiters of law, it should come as no surprise that devils are unusually common in Cheliax and the neighboring realms.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Dragon">
    <comment>Dragons are rightfully counted among the most legendary of monsters in the Inner Sea region. Most prefer to dwell in remote lairs, swooping down to interact with humanity only when their violent tempers push them to raid. Good dragons may seem less common than their evil kin, but only because they have less of an urge to mingle with humanoids.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Genie">
    <comment>The nation of Qadira has a long history with genies, but geniekind’s involvement with the Inner Sea region is certainly not limited to that nation. They serve as architects and creators of impossibilities on the isle of Jalmeray, and in Katapesh they are rumored to be infused into the very stone and soil of the land.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Giant">
    <comment>Countless tribes and varieties of these massive humanoids rule the rugged reaches of the world, from volcanic mountain ranges and stinking marshlands to trackless badlands and steaming jungles. They were used as slaves in ancient Thassilon, where they were ruled by magic-infused rune giants and forced to erect enormous monuments that remain to this day in Varisia, Belkzen, and the Lands of the Linnorm Kings. But now the giant tribes of northern Avistan are scattered across the land, largely unaware they once had a society that was destroyed and reshaped by the ancient empire of Thassilon.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Gnoll">
    <comment>Hyena-headed gnolls, ever seeking new slaves to perform menial labor, make for unreliable mercenaries but excel at hunting intelligent prey. Gnolls dwell primarily in northern Garund and are particularly common in Osirion, Katapesh, and Nex. Indeed, gnolls can be found operating openly as bodyguards, mercenaries, and slavers in cities like Katapesh.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Goblinoid">
    <comment>Goblins are certainly the most widespread and recognized goblinoids, but their taller, more militaristic hobgoblin kin rule the new kingdom of Oprak near Lake Encarthan. The looming, murderous creatures known as bugbears remain loners who eschew social structures, preferring to pursue their sadistic hobbies on their own.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Kobold">
    <comment>Industrious and fecund, kobolds thrive anywhere they can, often dwelling in narrow confines and twisting burrows in the hinterlands of rural regions or spreading throughout the sewers of urban centers. These small, reptilian humanoids share many traits with dragons— but courage, might, and an intimidating presence are certainly not among them!</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Leshy">
    <comment>The first leshys were grown by druids as minions, but over time these strange, plantlike creatures have diversified and now take many forms. Leshys have yet to organize or form nations of their own, but considering how quickly their numbers have grown and how swiftly they adapt to new regions, a leshy nation seems all but guaranteed in the near future.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Lizardfolk">
    <comment>Once widespread in Avistan and Garund, the isolationist lizardfolk, also known as iruxis, have been forced farther and farther into their forests and swamps by climate change and the rapid expansion of other humanoids. Normally peaceful, lizardfolk can be driven to war by encroaching civilization and power-hungry lizardfolk leaders—the latter are disturbingly common in the Mwangi Expanse and the River Kingdoms.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Orc">
    <comment>Most orcs currently regard the Hold of Belkzen as their ancestral land, despite the fact that they once called the upper reaches of the Darklands home. After living in a violent and brutal culture built on conquest and strength, some orcs of the Hold of Belkzen have begun to consider other means of securing their lands.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Planar Scion">
    <comment>A wide variety of planar scions dwell in the Inner Sea region, including the descendants of celestials and fiends who have mixed their bloodlines with those of mortals, and other lineages that arose from the influence of the Elemental Planes. In Cheliax, those who exhibit diabolic influences are particularly despised, as the leaders of that nation see them as examples of mortals who succumbed to fiendish influence instead of commanding devils as minions and slaves.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Serpentfolk">
    <comment>Serpentfolk once ruled the second layer of the Darklands along with much of the surface of Garund and Avistan. Azlant’s expansion into the Inner Sea region long before Earthfall led to a terrible war between the two peoples. When Azlant proved the victor, the surviving serpentfolk fled into the Darklands; they are nearly extinct today.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Undead"/>
  <row name="Construct"/>
</root>