<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
  <location name="The Great Beyond">
  </location>
  <location name="Inner Sphere">
    <location>The Great Beyond</location>
  </location>
  <location name="Material Plane">
    <location>Inner Sphere</location>
  </location>
  <location name="Elemental Planes">
    <location>Inner Sphere</location>
    <comment>The Elemental Planes surround the Material Plane like layered shells, with the Plane of Air on the inside, transitioning to the Plane of Water, then to the Plane of Earth, and finally to the Plane of Fire, in something of a reversal of order in which these elements most often appear on habitable planets.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Plane of Positive Energy">
    <location>Inner Sphere</location>
    <comment>The planes of Positive and Negative Energy are also within the Inner Sphere, their opposing nodes of life and death, creation and destruction, light and dark forming the start and the end of all existence.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Plane of Negative Energy">
    <location>Inner Sphere</location>
    <comment>The planes of Positive and Negative Energy are also within the Inner Sphere, their opposing nodes of life and death, creation and destruction, light and dark forming the start and the end of all existence.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Outer Sphere">
    <location>The Great Beyond</location>
    <comment>Here the gods dwell and the souls of the dead gather to be judged by the goddess of the dead, Pharasma, atop the spire in the realm that is her Boneyard. Anything is possible in the Outer Sphere, and its realms are as much manifestations of philosophies and belief as anything else. From the towering mountain of Heaven to the endless gulfs of the demon-held Abyss, be it the agonizing pit of Hell or the boundless wonders of Elysium, all of reality is represented within the Outer Sphere. Over time this reality erodes away and is recycled back into the raw material of life within the Positive Energy Plane.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Ethereal Plane">
    <location>The Great Beyond</location>
    <comment>the ghost world, which overlays the Inner Sphere</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Astral Plane">
    <location>The Great Beyond</location>
    <comment>the dizzying vastness of the Astral Plane, which overlays almost all reality and fills the seemingly endless gulf between the Inner Sphere and the Outer Sphere</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="First World">
    <location>The Great Beyond</location>
    <comment>fey-haunted plane, which overlay the Material Plane</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Shadow Plane">
    <location>The Great Beyond</location>
    <comment>sinister plane, which overlay the Material Plane</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Dreamlands">
    <location>The Great Beyond</location>
  </location>
  <location name="Dimension of Time">
    <location>The Great Beyond</location>
  </location>
  <location name="Golarion">
    <location>Material Plane</location>
    <comment>Golarion is but one of 11 worlds that orbit its sun.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Akiton">
    <location>Material Plane</location>
    <comment>Golarion’s closest neighbor planet.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Castrovel">
    <location>Material Plane</location>
    <comment>Golarion’s closest neighbor planet. Elves originally hail from Castrovel.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Aucturn">
    <location>Material Plane</location>
    <comment>Even the farthest planet, remote Aucturn, has influenced Golarion, with its alien inhabitants exerting a sinister touch on the world that recently put the entire planet in peril.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Inner Sea">
    <location>Golarion</location>
    <comment>The Inner Sea region consists of the continent of Avistan and the northern portion of the continent of Garund.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Isle of Kortos">
    <location>Inner Sea</location>
    <comment>also known as Starstone Isle</comment>
    <comment>The Isle of Kortos, also known as Starstone Isle, has a similarly diverse ecosystem. The verdant forests and grasslands of the west provide many of the resources Absalom needs, but to the east, the rugged stony desert known as the Scrape, the dangerous Riven Hills, and the newly formed necromantic wasteland known as the Tyrant’s Grasp present far harsher climates. The Isle of Erran, just north of Starstone Isle, hosts the second-largest city in the area, Escadar. A rough seaport with more than its share of shady dealings and dangerous types, Escadar also hosts large shipyards and maintains a strong navy that helps to keep the surrounding waters of the Inner Sea safe. A number of smaller islands also skirt the coast of the Isle of Kortos—some barren, some serving as hideouts for criminals and outcasts.</comment>
    <comment>Rising from the center of the Isle of Kortos are the Kortos Mounts, a short but rugged range of tors that have, over the years, been ruled by minotaurs, harpies, dragons, and worse. A few treacherous passes allow travel through the mountains, but with the northern shore of the Isle of Kortos being dominated by the soggy tangles of Dunmire, these northern reaches offer little to draw anyone other than bandits and adventurers into these still-untamed lands.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Starstone Isle">
    <comment>also known as Isle of Kortos</comment>
    <equivalent_to>Isle of Kortos</equivalent_to>
  </location>
  <location name="Absalom">
    <location>Isle of Kortos</location>
    <comment>At the heart of the Inner Sea stands the Isle of Kortos, raised from the waters thousands of years ago as Aroden’s first deific act. This amazing feat marks the dawn of the Age of Enthronement and the first year of the Absalom Reckoning calendar. The city of Absalom itself, the largest in the Inner Sea region, sprawls on the southern shore of this isle, and at the city’s heart stands the legendary Starstone Cathedral. Within the walls of this structure, the Starstone ever waits to test its next supplicants—the few mortals who pass this mystic test become gods themselves. This has made Absalom an oft-besieged metropolis, but in its nearly 5,000 years, it has never once fallen.</comment>
    <comment>Absalom, called by many the City at the Center of the World, boasts a population of over 300,000, and its culture is a true melting pot in both ancestry and belief. Even the city’s architecture reflects this, as one might expect of a settlement of its age. From the towering and majestic temples of the Ascendant Court to the close-packed shops and guildhalls of the Petal District and the sagging shanties in the Puddles, Absalom’s neighborhoods never fail to present a memorable skyline. Many world-reaching organizations were born in Absalom, notably the Pathfinder Society.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Avistan">
    <location>Golarion</location>
    <location>Inner Sea</location>
  </location>
  <location name="Garund">
    <location>Golarion</location>
    <location>Inner Sea</location>
    <comment>Garund itself extends further south, and its southern reaches are home to several unique ancestries and cultures.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Casmaron">
    <location>Golarion</location>
    <comment>As one travels east from the Inner Sea, the vast expanse of the continent of Casmaron stretches beyond the horizon. With the immense inland Castrovin Sea at its heart, Casmaron is the largest of Golarion’s continents and home to some of its oldest and most successful empires.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Tian Xia">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Tien</relates_to>
    <location>Golarion</location>
    <comment>Farther east of Casmaron lies the continent of Tian Xia, a region often called the Dragon Empires.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="The Crown of the World">
    <location>Golarion</location>
    <comment>The northern section of Tian Xia connects to Golarion’s northernmost continent, a frozen reach known as the Crown of the World. This continent forms a bridge between Tian Xia and Avistan over the north pole.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Sarusan">
    <location>Golarion</location>
    <comment>South of Tian Xia lies the mysterious continent of Sarusan, of which little is known due to the powerful storms and vexing currents that shroud its shores.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Azlant">
    <location>Golarion</location>
    <comment>Heading west from the Inner Sea region, sailors encounter the shattered remnants of lost Azlant, a ruined continent that hosted one of humanity’s first empires until it was destroyed during Earthfall.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Arcadia">
    <location>Golarion</location>
    <comment>Sailing farther west from these ruins eventually leads to the shores of Arcadia, a land with unusual magical traditions and powerful nations of its own.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Darklands">
    <location>Golarion</location>
    <comment>And beneath all of these lands, carved into the planet’s very crust, lie the twisting tunnels of the tripartite underground realm known collectively as the Darklands, which houses great horrors and dangers but equally great opportunities for triumph and treasure.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Broken Lands">
    <location>Inner Sea</location>
    <comment>Far to the north of Absalom sprawl the Broken Lands, nations and wildernesses united in their shared stature as fractured regions—places where life itself has taken a blow and the struggle to survive is simply part of daily reality. Not all of the Broken Lands are constantly fraught with peril, but regardless of where one might settle down in these parts’ tumultuous times, danger is rarely far from home.</comment>
    <comment>Elsewhere in the Broken Lands, the fractures are more spiritual. Razmiran, for example, is ruled by the living god Razmir, who demands the worship of all who dwell within his nation’s borders and brooks no competition of faith. His priests act as police throughout the land, brutally enforcing their deity’s laws. </comment>
    <comment>These western lands are truly broken, in a physical sense, for in the chaotic times at the dawn of the Age of Lost Omens, powerful agents of the demon lord Deskari tore a hole in reality. </comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Brevoy">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Varisian</relates_to>
    <location>Broken Lands</location>
    <comment>In some cases, the breaks are political. In the northeast, the nation of Brevoy has hung on the edge of civil war for many years, as the long-running feud between the traditional noble houses of Issia and the mercenary swordlords of Rostland maintain an ongoing state of tension that may be nearing a breaking point. But in the case of the oft-contested River Kingdoms, these political breaks have reached something of a draw, for here it is said that anyone might become the ruler of a nation—if they have the tenacity to seize the reins of rule.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Mendev">
    <location>Broken Lands</location>
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Hallit</relates_to>
    <comment>To the north in Mendev, these spiritual breaks are less obvious; this land struggles to reclaim its heritage in the wake of a century of occupation by a crusading force that, until a few years ago, stood as a bulwark against the demons who ruled the lands across the river to the west.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Sarkoris">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Hallit</relates_to>
    <location>Broken Lands</location>
    <comment>The resulting wound in the landscape allowed legions of demons to pour through and devastate the lands once known as Sarkoris. Although heroes of the Fifth Crusade recently defeated Deskari and closed the rift, these lands are still known as the Worldwound. The main threat has been quelled, but demons still inhabit the region, and the blighted landscape struggles to return to normal.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Numeria">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Hallit</relates_to>
    <location>Broken Lands</location>
    <comment>Perhaps the strangest of the Broken Lands lie near its heart. The rugged hills and plains of Numeria are home to many Kellid clans. However, in the distant past, the crash of a scientifically advanced starship brought strange aliens, mechanical monstrosities, and technological wonders to Golarion, but its fiery arrival left large reaches of the surrounding land blighted and blasted even to this day.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Eye of Dread">
    <location>Inner Sea</location>
    <comment>The heart of the continent of Avistan has rotted.</comment>
    <comment>Still farther to the north is the nation of Ustalav, a collection of counties each beset with its own manifestation of horror and fear, ranging from the nightmarishly cosmic to the dreadfully infernal.</comment>
    <comment>The Whispering Tyrant now rules a kingdom of the undead on the aptly named Isle of Terror in the center of Lake Encarthan. The nations lining Lake Encarthan’s shores have all suffered to varying degrees under the Whispering Tyrant’s renewed influence, and some are pursuing unlikely alliances to resist him. The lich is gathering his resources on the Isle of Terror, and none can say where or when he will strike next.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Ustalav">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Varisian</relates_to>
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Hallit</relates_to>
    <location>Eye of Dread</location>
  </location>
  <location name="Nirmathas">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Varisian</relates_to>
    <location>Eye of Dread</location>
    <comment>This region is dominated by Lake Encarthan, a large inland sea that was—until recently—a well-traveled hub for trade. To the southwest stands the militaristic nation of Molthune, which had long engaged in an intermittent war against its northern neighbor, Nirmathas, a wooded nation populated by folk who take their freedom seriously. An uprising of hobgoblins took advantage of this conflict, and while hostilities have since abated, the two nations now share their borders with a third: the newborn hobgoblin nation Oprak.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Hold of Belkzen">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Shoanti</relates_to>
    <location>Eye of Dread</location>
    <comment>North of these war-torn nations lie two other lands equally forged in the crucible of conflict. Until recently, the paladins and protectors of the small but strong nation of Lastwall stood fast against invasions from orcs, undead, and the like. The wild and rugged Hold of Belkzen, meanwhile, has long been held by those orcs, ever since they were driven up from the Darklands below by the dwarves during their Quest for Sky thousands of years ago.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="the Gravelands">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Varisian</relates_to>
    <location>Eye of Dread</location>
    <comment>It was from Ustalav that one of the greatest threats to the Inner Sea region emerged. The ancient lich Tar-Baphon— known as the Whispering Tyrant—has been defeated twice in the distant past—once by Aroden and once by the heroes of the Shining Crusade, but he has never been truly destroyed. When the magical seals that kept him imprisoned below the ominous tower of Gallowspire were finally sundered in 4719 ar, Tar-Baphon emerged, bringing with him devastation on such a scale that the one-time nation of Lastwall, which bore the brunt of his return to the world, has been utterly scoured. It exists now only as the Gravelands—the nation that once stood watch over undead uprisings now consigned to an undeath of its own. While heroes temporarily thwarted the Whispering Tyrant’s immediate plans shortly after he emerged, the lich remains an active menace.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Golden Road">
    <location>Inner Sea</location>
    <comment>Trade and travel rule the pathways of the so-called Golden Road, known for its shining sands and economic strength. Much of this region consists of sprawling desert wilderness, but this does not mean that the Golden Road is sparse in population. Coastlines and rivers serve as the lifeblood of this region, and some caravans brave the heat and dangers of the desert to trade across northern Garund. Some of the oldest nations in the Inner Sea region command this region, and ancient lore and valuable treasures can be found amid the shifting sands and storied cities.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Katapesh">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Vudrani</relates_to>
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Osiriani</relates_to>
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Kelish</relates_to>
    <location>Golden Road</location>
    <comment>The largest of these cities is the cosmopolitan Katapesh, where mercantilism is overseen by a strange group known as the Pactmasters. Much of the trade in Katapesh is in goods that can be freely exported or imported from throughout the Inner Sea region, but the city does just as much business in avenues normally regulated to the black markets of other societies.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Qadira">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Kelish</relates_to>
    <location>Golden Road</location>
    <comment>Qadira’s cities may not be as individually large as Katapesh, but the nation’s economy is perhaps the strongest. It’s certainly the oldest in the region, with support from the long-established Padishah Empire of Kelesh to the east. </comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Kelesh">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Kelish</relates_to>
    <location>Golden Road</location>
    <comment>This, coupled with the church of Sarenrae—perhaps the nation’s most successful cultural export to the rest of the Inner Sea region—has secured Qadira’s status as one of the most important centers of influence on the Golden Road.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Thuvia">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Osiriani</relates_to>
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Mwangi</relates_to>
    <location>Golden Road</location>
    <comment>To the west, the five city-states of Thuvia control a legendary alchemical concoction called the sun orchid elixir, which grants near-immortality to those who consume it. This treasured commodity is the keystone of Thuvia’s place in the Golden Road. </comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Rahadoum">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Osiriani</relates_to>
    <location>Golden Road</location>
    <comment>Further west, the nation of Rahadoum is perhaps the weakest mercantile link, but the fact that this society has eschewed the worship of gods to place its faith in the industry and talent of mortals alone gives the nation its own compelling draw.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Osirion">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Osiriani</relates_to>
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Kelish</relates_to>
    <location>Golden Road</location>
    <comment>At the center of the Golden Road lies mighty Osirion, one of the oldest nations of the Inner Sea region. While Osirion was for a time ruled by Qadira, the legacies and monuments of its early days still stand tall and are an indisputable and iconic source of pride and identity to its people. The influence of Osirion’s artisans, philosophers, and spellcasters has spread far and wide, particularly via the Esoteric Order of the Palatine Eye, far to the north in Ustalav, and the faith of Nethys, whose not-so-humble beginnings as a mortal wizard can be traced to the very beginning of Osirion’s history during the ancient Age of Destiny.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="High Seas">
    <location>Inner Sea</location>
    <comment>From fleets of pirates united under the Hurricane Queen of the Shackles to an ancient, subaquatic empire of shapechanging monsters led by the sinister veiled masters, the High Seas of Golarion present dangers both above and below the waves. Yet they also serve as important trade routes, with merchant ships traveling the waters to link powerful nations at opposite ends of continents. Sea captains brave the dangers of the High Seas hoping to partake in the fortunes to be made in trade, linking the ports of the Inner Sea itself to those on the shores of the Arcadian Ocean from the Mwangi Expanse to the Saga Lands.</comment>
    <comment>Other ports present their own complications. The port-city of Promise on the remote isle of Hermea a few hundred miles west of Avistan rewards well those who can negotiate the privilege of trade, but such honors are hard won, for the dragon who rules this closed society does not allow just anyone to visit. Rumors of what goes on beyond Promise’s dock district range from tales of a perfect society to those of an oppressive government that affords no free will. Farther to the north, the elves of the Mordant Spire are even more closed to visitors, and for most sailors, the only thing the Mordant Spire offers is an unmistakable landmark for navigation, as the twisting spire can be seen for miles.</comment>
    <comment>Of all the regions along the Avistani and Garundi coastlines, though, none are more hazardous to travel than the waters tortured by the Eye of Abendego. This immense hurricane first formed at the onset of the Age of Lost Omens, when storms wracked all of Golarion in the wake of Aroden’s death. Unlike those other storms, though, this hurricane remained. Its winds and storm surge have destroyed several nations and transformed a previously key gulf into a navigational nightmare. What strange force caused and perpetuates the Eye of Abendego has, to date, eluded all investigation.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="the Shackles">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Mwangi</relates_to>
    <location>High Seas</location>
    <comment>Piracy is one of the greatest dangers facing travel on the High Seas. The immense volcanic archipelago known as the Shackles serves as a haven for these pirates, with their Hurricane Queen providing just enough structure to keep them from going at each other’s throats. A great diversity of monsters and threats populate these islands, and the local pirates know which are safe and which to avoid. </comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Mediogalti Island">
    <location>High Seas</location>
    <comment>North of the Shackles lies Mediogalti Island. While its only significant port, Ilizmagorti, is a known safe harbor for pirates, it is the presence of the infamous Red Mantis assassins who rule the isle that gives this region its greatest infamy.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Impossible Lands">
    <location>Inner Sea</location>
    <comment>Magic allows for astounding feats, yet even those who consider themselves experts in the magical arts pause in wonder before the spectacles to be found in the Impossible Lands. What is taken for granted in these strange and eclectic nations would be all but impossible elsewhere.</comment>
    <comment>Only in the duchy of Alkenstar does life approach anything approximating normal, but even here the assumptions of the rest of the world are turned on their head. With magic being unpredictable, Alkenstar’s citizens have turned instead to technology. The nation is home to metallurgists and machinists, and the art of gunsmithing gives them an excellent advantage in this part of the world. Exports of firearms have steadily increased over the years, and Alkenstar is emerging as a significant power of its own as a result.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Geb">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Osiriani</relates_to>
    <location>Impossible Lands</location>
    <comment>Take Geb as an example. Here, the living are the minority, and undeath is the predominant way of life. Cruelty, sadism, and violence are the norm in Geb, as one might expect of a land ruled by a violent, undead dictator. This ghost, for whom the country was named, has ruled his nation for thousands of years, although for the past several centuries the day-to-day rule of the land fell to his queen, Arazni. Her recent disappearance (many would instead say “escape”) and abandonment of her duties have invigorated the ghost sovereign to once again take active leadership of his benighted realm.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Nex">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Vudrani</relates_to>
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Osiriani</relates_to>
    <location>Impossible Lands</location>
    <comment>Geb has opposed its northern neighbor, Nex, for the entirety of its existence. Also named after its ruler, Nex is a cosmopolitan realm where magic is mundane. Nex himself has been missing for ages, yet in his absence the Arclords have ruled quite effectively. Here, golems patrol the streets, and the practice of fleshwarping is an accepted and legitimate industry.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Mana Wastes">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Osiriani</relates_to>
    <location>Impossible Lands</location>
    <comment>Between these two opposed nations lies a stretch of land known as the Mana Wastes, a blasted and blighted badland formed by the ancient wars between Nex and Geb. The very magic of these lands is damaged—or in many reaches dead entirely—and peculiar mutants flop and prowl through the ruins in search of prey.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Jalmeray">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Vudrani</relates_to>
    <location>Impossible Lands</location>
    <comment>Across the waters of the Obari Ocean lies the final realm of the Impossible Lands: the island nation of Jalmeray. Here it isn’t magic alone that allows for impossibilities but also focused self-control and perfection of the spirit. The people of Jalmeray have accomplished astounding physical feats and achieved remarkable intellectual insights using nothing more than ancient traditions of mysticism and self-perfection.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Vudra">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Vudrani</relates_to>
    <location>Jalmeray</location>
  </location>
  <location name="Mwangi Expanse">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Mwangi</relates_to>
    <location>Inner Sea</location>
    <comment>The Mwangi Expanse is home to a wide array of civilizations, both past and present, even as it holds the largest stretch of wilderness in the Inner Sea region. In fact, one of the first civilizations to rise from the ashes after Earthfall rose here in this land—the nation of Shory and its astounding flying cities, from which many modern customs of magic stem.</comment>
    <comment>Some Mwangi cities and kingdoms were lost far more recently than those ancient wonders. When the Eye of Abendego formed just over a century ago, its winds and waves flooded two significant realms along Garund’s west coast. Where once stood the nations of Lirgen and Yamasa now stretch only the Sodden Lands, a swath of swampland and salt marshes held by rival gangs of scavengers and monsters. Even more recently, a powerful city-state in the heart of the Mwangi Jungle, Usaro, fell when its brutal leader, Ruthazek the Gorilla King, was slain by adventurers. Usaro has been without a leader for only a few short years, but already its violent inhabitants have caused significant damage in their anarchic rioting. A long lineage of demonically infused Gorilla Kings has ruled Usaro over the centuries, and so a new one will likely soon rise to seize control of Usaro, for the moment this sinister region lacks a head to focus its wrath.</comment>
    <comment>Despite these instances of ruin and destruction, the Mwangi Expanse hosts a wealth of diverse and powerful city-states within its reaches. In Bloodcove, the ruthless mercantile league of the Aspis Consortium rules. Farther south along the coast stands Senghor, whose stance against both piracy and slavery place the city in stark contrast to its northern neighbor. The city-state of Nantambu lies far upstream from Bloodcove on the Vanji River, where its citizens carry on the ancient traditions of Old-Mage Jatembe in combining arcane and primal magic. Far to the southeast stands Mzali, which lies under the oppressive rule of the undead child-king Walkena, though a group of dissidents called the Bright Lions works to build resistance to the mummy’s reign. Then there is the city of Kibwe, where within its walls dwell an eclectic mix of people who have journeyed from afar to seek trade and companionship.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Vidrian">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Mwangi</relates_to>
    <location>Mwangi Expanse</location>
    <comment>Farther south from these independent city-states lies the recently freed nation of Vidrian. Originally established as the Chelish colony of Sargava, Vidrian has now seized its own destiny and cast off its colonial shackles. In so doing, the young nation has exposed itself to the predations of pirates and worse, yet to its citizens, freedom from oppression is well worth that price.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Old Cheliax">
    <location>Inner Sea</location>
    <comment>At its height, the empire of Cheliax had holdings that reached from Varisia to Garund and east all the way to Galt. Aroden was prophesized to return to the world of mortals to usher in a new Age of Glory, and those prophecies predicted the Chelish city of Westcrown would be the point of his arrival. Instead, his death ignited a civil war that lasted for decades. When the Thrice-Damned House of Thrune emerged as victor, Cheliax had forever changed. Under House Thrune’s rule, Cheliax transformed into a nation that viewed Hell as a blueprint for government. The church of Asmodeus became Cheliax’s official state religion, and diabolism its most powerful philosophy. The devil had come home to rule, and while the nation’s politicians and leaders claimed that they maintained control of their fate— and House Thrune had merely formed an alliance with Hell to maintain its power and keep order—the nation’s internal and external enemies know better.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Old Cheliax">
    <comment>Many of Cheliax’s outlying provinces—such as Andoran, Galt, and Vidrian—revolted and became their own nations. The nation of Isger remains, at least on paper, a thrall. Cheliax values Isger for its important position as a trade route to the Lake Encarthan region, but when Isger was wracked by the violence of the Goblinblood Wars several decades ago, House Thrune did little to provide aid. As the repercussions of the Whispering Tyrant’s return to power send ripples of nervous dread through the land, Isger’s people grow fearful that they lack not only their own political strength but also that of their supposed protector, and as a result, Isger is one of the lands in the Inner Sea region most in need of heroes.</comment>
    <comment>Recently, several uprisings within Cheliax have further tested the nation’s resolve. After a devastating nautical loss in the Shackles resulted in Vidrian’s independence, a new Iomedaean rebellion called the Glorious Reclamation threatened Cheliax from within. House Thrune and the Asmodean church defeated the Glorious Reclamation, but at a price—a simultaneous rebellion was successful, with a group of rebels called the Silver Ravens negotiating the successful secession of the new nation of Ravounel.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Nidal">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Varisian</relates_to>
    <location>Old Cheliax</location>
    <comment>North of Cheliax, the shadowy nation of Nidal remains the diabolic nation’s only real ally. A theocracy ruled by the church of Zon-Kuthon, Nidal is the oldest nation on Avistan, for its people turned to the Midnight Lord for protection during the Age of Darkness after Earthfall. Today, pain and dread are comforts to the citizens of Nidal, and millennia of rule under a church that revels in pain have left them inured to agony and welcoming of loss.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Saga Lands">
    <location>Inner Sea</location>
    <comment>While the opportunity for epic adventure exists throughout the world, in recent years it seems the Saga Lands have produced the most notorious and legendary tales. These sprawling northern reaches feature kingdoms ruled by vikings and witches, realms home to mammoth-riding Kellid clans, and a frontier land of free cities and dangerous wilderness—all of which are steeped in the ancient legacy of the long-gone empire of Thassilon.</comment>
    <comment>Millennia ago, the nation of Thassilon was ruled by the sinful, tyrannical runelords. These wizards carved out legends intended to last for an eternity, but even the mighty runelords succumbed to the devastation of Earthfall. The seven reigning runelords of that time retreated into the safety of extradimensional domains, and for eons they slumbered, until they began to wake in 4707 ar.</comment>
    <comment>Recently, a new nation has risen in the Saga Lands. After the runelords were defeated, two surviving runelords decided to adjust their traditions to fit this strange new world they found themselves in. Now the fledgling nation of New Thassilon sprawls along the northern border of Varisia, and it remains to be seen if its rulers will fully adopt a more peaceful path, or if it is but a matter of time before the old traditions of sin and violence rise once again.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Varisia">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Varisian</relates_to>
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Shoanti</relates_to>
    <location>Saga Lands</location>
    <comment>The frontier realm of Varisia, once the heart of Thassilon, bore the brunt of the wrath of the first wakened runelord, an avaricious sadist named Karzoug. A band of unlikely heroes emerged from the small coastal town of Sandpoint to eventually face and defeat Karzoug, yet his wakening soon roused other slumbering runelords, and a new band of heroes was forced to defeat the risen tyrants.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Lands of the Linnorm Kings">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Skald</relates_to>
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Tien</relates_to>
    <comment>Lands of the Linnorm Kings</comment>
    <location>Saga Lands</location>
  </location>
  <location name="Irrisen">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Skald</relates_to>
    <location>Saga Lands</location>
    <comment>While the neighboring Lands of the Linnorm Kings, Realms of the Mammoth Lords, and witch-haunted Irrisen never faced direct repercussions from the runelords, these northern lands hold dangers of their own. A long-running cold war between the vikings of the Linnorm Kingdoms and the winter witches of Irrisen to the east finally came to a sputtering end when a daughter of the immortal witch Baba Yaga attempted to defy her mother and usurp Irrisen’s traditions of rule. While the eternal winter of Irrisen set in place by Baba Yaga endures, its new ruler, Anastasia, may prove to be the first benevolent presence to sit on the throne in centuries. </comment>
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Hallit</relates_to>
  </location>
  <location name="Realm of the Mammoth Lords">
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Tien</relates_to>
    <location>Saga Lands</location>
    <relates_to object_class="Language">Hallit</relates_to>
    <comment>Farther to the east, the Kellid clans of the Realm of the Mammoth Lords played their own pivotal roles in defying the demons of the Worldwound.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Shining Kingdoms">
    <location>Inner Sea</location>
    <comment>To the west, the democratic nation of Andoran stands as a rising star on the international stage. Ever since the province seceded from the nation of Cheliax, Andoran’s military has helped to stem the flow of slavery, and its heroes have stood tall against all manner of peril to the common folk. But the future doesn’t look entirely bright for Andoran, for with Cheliax’s recent upsets, rumors flow that House Thrune may seek to reclaim control of its wayward thrall. Given the looming threat of the Whispering Tyrant, an all-out war between these two powerful nations could be disastrous.</comment>
    <comment>Northeast of Andoran sprawls the dwarven city-states of the Five Kings Mountains. No strangers to war, both against enemies and among themselves, the dwarves of the Five Kings remain allies of Andoran but have their own troubles that command most of their attention. To the west of the dwarven realm, the rich and powerful nation of Druma controls nearly half of the lake’s southern shoreline and uses its position to bolster its coffers and further the teachings of the Prophecies of Kalistrade, a philosophy that teaches that wealth can be achieved through adherence to strict and abstemious practices.</comment>
    <comment>Still farther east is the nation of Galt. Wracked for decades by a self-perpetuating series of rebellions and revolutions, this land has been torn apart from within over and over. Its people are tired and desperate as they continue to live what lives they can in the shadow of the final blades—powerful magical guillotines that claim the souls of those they decapitate. If any of the regions of the Shining Kingdoms is poised for significant change in the near future, it is surely revolution-wracked Galt.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Taldor">
    <location>Shining Kingdoms</location>
    <comment>The empire of Taldor was historically the heart of the Shining Kingdoms. In the early Age of Enthronement, Taldor sent several Armies of Exploration to expand the nation’s borders and colonize the surrounding lands. Today, Taldor is but a shadow of its former glory, but after a recent bout of internal strife, a progressive new empress has claimed the crown, and Taldor may be on the path to recover its old glory for the first time in centuries.</comment>
  </location>
  <location name="Kyonin">
    <location>Shining Kingdoms</location>
    <comment>Northeast of Druma lie the forested elven lands of Kyonin, one of Avistan’s oldest nations. This land belonged to the elves long before Earthfall, but for thousands of years after that devastation, they left their realm abandoned. In that time, a powerful demon named Treerazer seized control of the forest’s southern reaches, corrupting the terrain into a swampy, desolate mire called Tanglebriar. Although the elves have returned, they’ve been unable to force Treerazer from their southern border.</comment>
  </location>
</root>