<?xml version="1.0"?>
<root>
  <row name="Bulwark">
    <comment>The armor covers you so completely that it provides benefits against some damaging effects.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Comfort">
    <comment>The armor is so comfortable that you can rest normally while wearing it.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Flexible">
    <comment>The armor is flexible enough that it doesn’t hinder most actions.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Noisy">
    <comment>This armor is loud and likely to alert others to your presence.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Chain" subclass="SpecializationEffect">
    <comment>The armor is so flexible it can bend with a critical hit and absorb some of the blow.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Composite" subclass="SpecializationEffect">
    <comment>The numerous overlapping pieces of this armor protect you from piercing attacks.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Leather" subclass="SpecializationEffect">
    <comment>The thick second skin of the armor disperses blunt force to reduce bludgeoning damage.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Plate" subclass="SpecializationEffect">
    <comment>The sturdy plate provides no purchase for a cutting edge.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Cloth">
  </row>
  <row name="Axe" subclass="SpecializationEffect">
  </row>
  <row name="Bomb" subclass="SpecializationEffect">
  </row>
  <row name="Bow" subclass="SpecializationEffect">
  </row>
  <row name="Brawling" subclass="SpecializationEffect">
  </row>
  <row name="Club" subclass="SpecializationEffect">
  </row>
  <row name="Dart" subclass="SpecializationEffect">
  </row>
  <row name="Flail" subclass="SpecializationEffect">
  </row>
  <row name="Hammer" subclass="SpecializationEffect">
  </row>
  <row name="Knife" subclass="SpecializationEffect">
  </row>
  <row name="Pick" subclass="SpecializationEffect">
  </row>
  <row name="Polearm" subclass="SpecializationEffect">
  </row>
  <row name="ShieldWeapon" subclass="SpecializationEffect">
  </row>
  <row name="Sling" subclass="SpecializationEffect">
  </row>
  <row name="Spear" subclass="SpecializationEffect">
  </row>
  <row name="Sword" subclass="SpecializationEffect">
  </row>
  <row name="Bludgeoning" subclass="DamageTypePhysical">
    <comment>comes from weapons and hazards that deal blunt-force trauma, like a hit from a club or being dashed against rocks</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Piercing" subclass="DamageTypePhysical">
    <comment>is dealt from stabs and punctures, whether from a dragon’s fangs or the thrust of a spear</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Slashing" subclass="DamageTypePhysical">
    <comment>is delivered by a cut, be it the swing of the sword or the blow from a scythe blades trap</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Agile">
  </row>
  <row name="Attached">
  </row>
  <row name="Backstabber">
  </row>
  <row name="Backswing">
  </row>
  <row name="Deadly">
  </row>
  <row name="Disarm">
  </row>
  <row name="Dwarf">
  </row>
  <row name="Elf">
  </row>
  <row name="Fatal">
  </row>
  <row name="Finesse">
  </row>
  <row name="Forceful">
  </row>
  <row name="Free-Hand">
  </row>
  <row name="Gnome">
  </row>
  <row name="Goblin">
  </row>
  <row name="Grapple">
  </row>
  <row name="Halfling">
  </row>
  <row name="Jousting">
  </row>
  <row name="Monk">
  </row>
  <row name="Nonlethal" subclass="DamageType">
    <comment>are used to knock creatures unconscious instead of kill them.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Orc">
  </row>
  <row name="Parry">
  </row>
  <row name="Propulsive">
  </row>
  <row name="Reach">
  </row>
  <row name="Shove">
  </row>
  <row name="Sweep">
  </row>
  <row name="Thrown">
  </row>
  <row name="Trip">
  </row>
  <row name="Twin">
  </row>
  <row name="Two-Hand">
  </row>
  <row name="Unarmed">
  </row>
  <row name="Versatile">
  </row>
  <row name="Volley">
  </row>
  <row name="Uncommon">
  </row>
  <row name="Matter">
    <comment>Also called body, material essence, or physical essence, matter is the fundamental building block that makes up all physical things in the universe. The arcane and primal traditions are especially attuned toward manipulating and shaping matter. Spells that are used to create or alter matter most often come from the conjuration, evocation, or transmutation schools.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Spirit">
    <comment>Also called soul, ethereal essence, or spiritual essence, spirit is an otherworldly building block that makes up a being’s immaterial and immortal self. The spirit travels through the Ethereal Plane and into the Great Beyond after the death of the physical body. The spirit is most easily affected by divine and occult spells. Spirit spells are usually of the divination or necromancy schools.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Mind">
    <comment>Also called thought, mental, or astral essence, mind is what allows thinking creatures to have rational thoughts, ideas, plans, logic, and memories. Mind touches even non-sapient creatures like animals, though in a more limited capacity. Arcane and occult casters usually excel at mind spells. Spells that use mind essence are usually found in the divination, enchantment, and illusion schools.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Life">
    <comment>Also called heart, faith, instinct, or vital essence, life represents the animating universal force within all things. Whereas matter provides the base materials for a body, life keeps it alive and well. This essence is responsible for unconscious responses and belief, such as ancestral instincts and divine guidance. The divine and primal traditions hold power over life. Life spells are usually necromancy.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Material component">
    <comment>A material component is a bit of physical matter consumed in the casting of the spell.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Somatic component">
    <comment>A somatic component is a specific hand movement or gesture that generates a magical nexus.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Verbal component">
    <comment>A verbal component is a vocalization of words of power.</comment>
    <leadsTo>Spend all air</leadsTo>
  </row>
  <row name="Focus component">
    <comment>A focus is an object that funnels the magical energy of the spell.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Secret">
    <comment>Sometimes you as the player shouldn’t know the exact result and effect of a check.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Acid" subclass="DamageTypeEnergy">
    <comment>can be delivered by gases, liquids, and certain solids that dissolve flesh, and sometimes harder materials</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Cold" subclass="DamageTypeEnergy">
    <comment>freezes material by way of contact with chilling gases and ice</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Electricity" subclass="DamageTypeEnergy">
    <comment>comes from the discharge of powerful lightning and sparks</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Fire" subclass="DamageTypeEnergy">
    <comment>burns through heat and combustion</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Sonic" subclass="DamageTypeEnergy">
    <comment>assaults matter with high-frequency vibration and sound waves</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Positive" subclass="DamageTypeEnergy">
    <comment>harms only undead creatures, withering undead bodies and disrupting incorporeal undead</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Negative" subclass="DamageTypeEnergy">
    <comment>saps life, damaging only living creatures</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Force" subclass="DamageTypeEnergy">
    <comment>Powerful and pure magical energy can manifest itself as force damage. Few things can resist this type of damage—not even incorporeal creatures such as ghosts and wraiths.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Chaotic" subclass="DamageTypeAlignment">
    <comment>harms only lawful creatures</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Evil" subclass="DamageTypeAlignment">
    <comment>harms only good creatures</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Good" subclass="DamageTypeAlignment">
    <comment>harms only evil creatures</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Lawful" subclass="DamageTypeAlignment">
    <comment>harms only chaotic creatures</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Mental" subclass="DamageType">
    <comment>Sometimes an effect can target the mind with enough psychic force to actually deal damage to the creature. Mindless creatures and those with only programmed or rudimentary intelligence are often immune to mental damage and effects.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Poison" subclass="DamageType">
    <comment>Venoms, toxins and the like can deal poison damage, which affects creatures by way of contact, ingestion, inhalation, or injury. In addition to coming from monster attacks, alchemical items, and spells, poison damage is often caused by ongoing afflictions.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Bleed" subclass="DamageType">
    <comment>This is persistent damage that represents loss of blood. As such, it has no effect on nonliving creatures or living creatures that don’t need blood to live. Weaknesses and resistances to physical damage apply. Bleed damage ends automatically if you’re healed to your full Hit Points.</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Precision" subclass="DamageType">
    <comment>increase the attack’s listed damage, using the same damage type, rather than tracking a separate pool of damage</comment>
  </row>
  <row name="Virulent"/>
  <row name="On self"/>
  <row name="On target"/>
  <row name="On all party"/>
  <row name="Fortune"/>
  <row name="Without trigger"/>
  <row name="Does not trigger reaction"/>
  <row name="Trigger reaction"/>
  <row name="Move">
    <uses>Grid movement rule</uses>
    <uses>Moving through space of other creature</uses>
    <uses>Moving through space of object</uses>
    <uses>Share space with other creature</uses>
    <leadsTo>Change position</leadsTo>
  </row>
</root>